Donkey Kong! It's a game! Let's do that, I guess. I don't know.
And because I love you and hate sleep and a social life, I'm gonna be testing not one, not two, but three different AI algorithms.
I thought it'd be cool to, like, compare all the algorithms I've used on previous projects on a single project and see who wins.
I'm talking the best of the best. We got genetic algorithm, we got neural evolution of augmented topologies,
and we got proximal policy optimization going head-to-head.
But we're getting ahead of ourselves. Game first, AI later.
Okay, let's make Donkey Kong.
Okay, player onscreen done. It's a square. Very nice. Creative work. Nice.
Now, I could move around the player using Unity's built-in physics system,
but that will animate the player way too smoothly, and in order for it to have that classic arcade feel,
it's gotta have a bit of jank movement in it.
So, unfortunately, I'm gonna have to be a big boy and code the physics myself.
Okay, let's move that player. Can it go right? Yes.
Can it go left? Close enough.
Can it jump? Ah, well, yeah. Ah, close.
Gravity? Yes.
Less gravity? Yes.
Fuck yeah, everything is coming together. This must be what God felt like.
Dude, you're just moving a square around the-
Sideways jumping? Yes.
Sideways jumping and gravity at the same time? Yes.
Woo! Holy shit, he cannot be stopped.
Ground? No.
Oof.
Tutorial?
Turns true or false depending on weather. The move was successfully com-
Yes.
Ground? No.
Fuck.
This is getting annoying.
Ground? No.
That's actually pretty aesthetically pleasing, but it's not at all what we're looking for.
Ground? Oh? No?
But we're close. We're close and I can feel it.
Ground? N-
Yes. Yeah.
Fucking easy. Bit of a challenge next time.
Okay, so the ground's done and it's all looking pretty good now.
I know it's nothing revolutionary, but you know, baby steps.
So, the problem with Donkey Kong is that we gotta handle these little steps.
And it's not like a smooth slope either. It's a bunch of individual steps.
You see, if I try this now, it's just gonna-
Oh. Oh, what the- What?
It already works.
I- I don't understand. It never works first try.
Fuck. This has never- This has never happened before.
Oh, I'm- I'm scared.
Oh, no. It's okay. It's okay.